Guide to the KUED-TV productions audio-visual collection 1966-2010
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Promontory, circa 2002; VHS videocassette (Cassette 53)
  Promontory takes the viewer on a journey back in time to the days when the nation struggled to build the transcontinental railroad. As construction armies raced east and west, it soon became clear that they would meet in the most unlikely spot in the nation: The Utah Territory under the leadership of Brigham Young. What happened next would forever change the face of Utah and the West. 57 minutes.
- The Spirit of Fort Douglas, circa 2002; VHS videocassette (Cassette 54)
  Directed and Produced by Joe Prokop
  Documentary detailing the history of Fort Douglas, which was originally a federal camp overlooking Mormon pioneers, then a training ground for military personnel and later a prison for people feared to be a threat to national security. 55 minutes.
- Twenty Years in Twenty Minutes, circa 1992; VHS videocassette (Cassette 55)
  A short video history of KUED-TV. 20 minutes.
- Battalion, undated; VHS videocassette, DVD (Cassette 56)
  Produced by Nancy Green and Ken Verdoia.
  Documentary detailing the story of the Mormon Battalion during the U.S. war with Mexico.
- No Safe Place: Domestic Violence, circa 1996; VHS videocassette (Cassette 57)
- Tell Me, circa 1966; VHS videocassette (Cassette 58)
  24 minutes
- Twenty Years in Twenty Minutese, circa 1978; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 59)
  A documentary history of Television Station KUED, Salt Lake City, broadcast January 20, 1978. Includes brief segments from important programs televised over KUED during its first twenty years. 20 minutes.
- University of Utah at 150: Line Cut, 1999 February 07; Fuji D3001 videocassette (Cassette 60)
- University of Utah at 150: Line Cut, 2000 February 07; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 61)
- University of Utah at 150: Former Presidents with Questions and Answers, 2000 February 07; VHS videocassette (Cassette 62)
- Sesquicentennial, 150 Years at the University of Utah, 2000; VHS videocassette (Cassette 63)
- Washington D.C, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 64)
- Crime Victims Reparation long version, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 65)
- Skull Valley: Radioactive Waste and the American West, circa 2001; VHS videocassette (Cassette 66)
  The vast landscape of Utah's West Desert has become a crossroads for a national energy, safety and accountability crisis. Already surrounded by military, chemical, and radiation hazards, the small Skull Valley Band of the Goshute Indian tripe may partner with a consortium of nuclear power utilities to store 80 million pounds of spent uranium fuel rods from the nation's nuclear power plants for up to 40 years. With federal approval, an above ground storage plan would move forward on the tribe's reservation lands, despite the opposition of Utah's governor, the state legislature, and public sentiment. Balanced and in-depth, Ken Verdoia's Skull Valley: Radioactive waste and the American West details a full-blown power struggle that pits government against government, culture against culture, and leaves little room for public concern to be addressed. It's one of the most compelling public policy crises of the new century, and at the center of the controversy is arguably the most lethal industrial waste ever produced by man. 90 minutes.
- Utah in the 1950's: Salt Lake City with Ted Capener, circa 2001; VHS videocassette (Cassette 67)
  It was the best of times. Everyone liked Ike, and they loved Mayor Earl J. Glade. City streets were vibrant and drive-in movies were the place to be. Women didn't go downtown without their hats and gloves. Movie houses like the Southeast Theater were packed-and not by crowds dressed in jeans and T-shirts, but in coats, ties, dresses and heels. Ushers escorted droves of ticket-holders to the Technicolor world of Doris Day and Clark Gable. Host Ted Capener takes viewers on a nostalgic journey featuring archival photographs and personal anecdotges from people who remember the fifties best. Produced by Elizabeth Searles, Utah in the 50's: Salt Lake City with Ted Capener recalls a decade when cars were snazzy, malt shops ruled, and Elvis was King.
- Promontory, circa 2002; VHS videocassette (Cassette 68)
  57 minutes
- Utah: The National Parks, circa 2004; DVD (Disc 69)
  This symphony of sight and sound features the spectacular landscapes of Utah's national parks, with music from some of the world's greatest composers. Canyonlands National Park, Arches National Park, Bryce Canyon National Park, Capitol Reef National Park, Zion National Park. 56 minutes.
- Maynard Dixon: To the Desert Again, circa 2006; DVD (Disc 70)
  One hundred years ago, a solitary figure roamed the desert Southwest seeking to capture the endless sky and towering mesas in paint and poetry. His vision of the West was Matchless. Maynard Dixon survived the great destruction of San Francisco by earthquake and fire, the Great Depression, and the civilizing of the West. He spent over two decades sketching it for popular books and magazines, and then decades more on a question to find and portray it: the "real" West-the vast space, intense silence, and profound spirit of the land and its people. Discover the man and his art. 56 minutes.
- Green River: Divided Waters, circa 2009; DVD (Disc 71)
  Its whitewater formed the backdrop for one of the nation's great adventure stories. Some consider it the birthplace of the modern environmental movement and its waters still attract those who prize outdoor experiences. Now, it also attracts those who would use the water to sustain development for an energy-dependent nation and those who want to tap the river to quench booming populations in the West. What does the future hold for the Green River? 57 minutes.
- Secrets of the Lost Canyon, circa 2005; DVD (Disc 72)
  It is one of the most significant finds in North America in the past 50 years. Nested in the heart of Central Utah in Range Creek Canyon are the remains of a lost civilization that once thrived in the American Southwest. For 500 years, the Fremont Indians lived in parts of the Great Basin and Colorado Plateau as hunters, gatherers, and farmers. They left detailed art and symbols on the stone faces of canyons they inhabited and stored their grain high on cliff walls in well-built granaries that still survive. Then, 800 years ago, the Fremont seemingly disappeared. Today, University of Utah archeologists are surveying an entire canyon of more than 2,000 untouched Fremont Indian sites. This KUED documentary captures a range of issue and challenges that threaten efforts to understand the past. 57 minutes.
- Red Blood, Blue Blood: The Rivalry, 2010; DVD (Disc 73)
  It's a rivalry so powerful that office friendships turn cool, neighbors grow distant, even the faithful in church pews seem to split down the middle. It's the nose-to-nose, generations-old – and often hilarious – showdown between football fans of the University of Utah and Brigham Young University. Red Blood, Blue Blood: The Rivalry delivers first-hand stories through candid conversations with legendary coaches such as LaVell Edwards and Ron McBride. Broadcasters and writers such as Dick Rosetta, Bill Marcroft, and Paul James share side-splitting anecdotes from behind the scenes. But the greatest voice comes from the stands – from the men, women, and children who don the Red or Blue as a lifetime commitment and the often hilarious lengths they will go to defend their team. 56 minutes.
- Green River, Utah: A Desert Oasis, undated; 16mm film (Disc 74)
  John Wesley Powell was the first, in 1869, to document the area that would later become the town of Green River, Utah. Green River was initially inhabited by Anasazi and Fremont Indians; the town later became the site of oil well, as well as the "Utah Launch Complex," a missile launch site of the White Sands Missile Range. Green River has seen booms and busts, as the area, rich in uranium, swelled in size with the uranium rush of the 1950s, which later dwindled as interest in uranium waned, and which has lately become of interest due to the energy crisis. The beautiful backdrop of this small town has a rich history, and is still a site of outdoor exploration. Available on DVD, 28 minutes.